surveypal.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

Surveypal (and its parent/subsidiary company(ies) Surveypal Oy, and Surveypal Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  Surveypal is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Surveypal is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  Surveypal complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Surveypal is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Surveypal may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website[https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

## Information We Collect About You

When you contact us requesting a demo of our service, ask us questions regarding services or signing up for one of our Academy programs we will ask you for information such as your name, phone number and email address.

### Newsletters

When you sign up for our services, we will send you newsletter(s) or communications regarding products which may be of interest to you. If you no longer wish to receive these communications you can follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the email communications you receive or by contacting us at[helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com).

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

### Service Providers

We use other third parties such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

We may use third parties to assist us in selling Surveypal services. Information shared with such third party will be limited to client relationship information and information provided by potential customer. Information will only be used for Surveypal sales.

### Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

Surveypal collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes.

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

Surveypal has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Surveypal’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Surveypal to remove the data, we will respond to their request within a reasonable timeframe.

## Additional Information

### Sharing Personal Information

We will not share your personal information only as outlined within this privacy statement.

We may disclose your personal information  
– as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process  
– when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,  
– if Surveypal is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,  
– to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### Access to Personal Information

Upon request Surveypal will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by  
logging into your account and making the appropriate changes or by emailing us at[helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients as well as your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

### Security

The security of your personal information and our clients’ information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials) we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact[helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com).

### Blogs

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at[helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at[helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com).

### Tracking Technologies

Surveypal and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site and within our service. We may link the information stored in cookies to personal information you submit on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

As is true of most Web sites, we and our third party tracking-utility partner to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click[here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click[here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

### Social Media Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

### Links to Other Web Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Surveypal. Please be aware that we, Surveypal, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

### Changes to This Privacy Statement

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a prominent notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement you may contact us at [helpdesk@surveypal.com](mailto:helpdesk@surveypal.com) or via postal mail at Surveypal, Inc. 470 Ramona Street, Palo Alto 94301, CA.
